Inventory of the Konstantin Fotic Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Serbian Central National Committee (Srpski Centralni Narodni Odbor ? SCNO), 1932-1958 and undated (Box 28-41)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1958 and undated
    - Serbian and Yugoslav émigré organizations, 1941-1956
      - Jugoslavenski Narodni Odbor (Yugoslav National Committee), London, 1945-1948 (contd.) (Folder 38: 1-6)
    - Other nations' émigré organizations and committees, 1949-1954
      - Baltic States Freedom Committee, 1951-1952 (Folder 38: 7)
      - Bulgarian National Committee-Free and independent Bulgaria, 1953 (Folder 38: 8)
      - Committee for a Free Latvia, 1954 (Folder 38: 9)
      - Council of Free Czechoslovakia, 1949-1952 (Folder 38: 10)
      - Estonian National Council, 1951-1952 (Folder 38: 11)
      - Hungarian National Council, 1951-1954 (Folder 38: 12)
      - National Democratic Committee for a free Albania, 1954 (Folder 38: 13)
      - Polish Federalist Association in the United States, 1953 (Folder 38: 14)
      - Polish National Alliance in the United States of North America, 1951 (Folder 38: 15)
      - Polish Political Council, 1951 (Folder 38: 16)
      - Rumanian National Committee, 1950 (Folder 38: 17)
      - Ukrainian National Council, 1952-1953 (Folder 38: 18)
      - Union of Polish Federalists, London, 1953 (Folder 38: 19)
    - International organizations, 1944-1956
      - General Assembly of the United Nations, 1948-1950 (Folder 38: 20)
      - Intergovernmental Committee for European migration, United States office, 1955 (Folder 38: 21)
      - International Peasant Union, 1947-1948 (Folder 38: 22)
      - National Committee for Free Europe, 1949-1953 (Folder 38: 23-27)
      - National Committees and Council of Central and Eastern European countries, 1951-1953 (Folder 38: 28-30)
      - United National Committees and Councils in Exile, 1954-1956 (Folder 39: 1)
      - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1944 (Folder 39: 2)
  - Reports, memoranda, and correspondence, 1932-1956.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Kraljevska vlada, untra?nja politika, 1932-1935 (Folder 39: 3)
    - Slovenia, 1943-1945 (Folder 39: 4)
    - Yugoslavia, 1944-1953 (Folder 39: 5-17)
    - Yugoslavia, 1944-1953 (contd.) (Folder 40: 1-4)
    - United Committee of South-Slavic Americans, Third annual meeting report, 1945 (Folder 40: 5)
    - "En Yougoslavie, rien de nouveau," Petkovic's report, 1945 (Folder 40: 6)
    - Members of the Yugoslav government under Tito, biography, 1945 (Folder 40: 7)
    - Yalta conference, 1945-1946 (Folder 40: 8)
    - "Le procès de Belgrade contre le général Dra?a Mihailovic,", 1946 (Folder 40: 9)
    - The Opium problem, 1946 (Folder 40: 10)
    - Stvaranje srpske civilne uprave pod nemackom okupacijom u 1941, 1946 (Folder 40: 11)
    - The Agrarian Federation, 1947 (Folder 40: 12)
    - Italy and Trieste, 1947-1948 (Folder 40: 13-16)
    - General Assembly of the United Nations, address, 1947 (Folder 40: 17)
    - Croatia, 1948-1951 (Folder 40: 18-19)
    - Ante Pavelic i Usta?e, 1949 (Folder 40: 20)
    - Albania, 1949 (Folder 40: 21)
    - "Memorandum on Support of the Genocide Convention,", 1951 (Folder 40: 22)
    - "Memorandum on Crimes of Genocide Committed by Croatian Ustachis during World War II,", 1951 (Folder 41: 1)
    - Odnosi sa Hrvatskom i Slovenijom, 1955-1957 (Folder 41: 2)
    - Provilnik o radu Izvr?nog odbora Srpskog Narodnog Centranlnog Odbora, undated (Folder 41: 3)
    - Untitled speeches, 1944-1945, 1956 (Folder 41: 4-6)
- Serbian National Federation (Srpski Narodni Savez - SNS), 1937-1956 (Folder 41)
  Consists of correspondence including enclosures, reports, memorandum, open letter, and clippings. Arranged by form
  - Correspondence, 1937-1952
    - 1937-1941 (Folder 41: 7)
    - 1942 (Folder 41: 8)
    - 1943-1944 (Folder 41: 9)
    - 1945 (Folder 41: 10-11)
    - 1946 (Folder 41: 12)
    - 1947 (Folder 41: 13)
    - 1948 (Folder 41: 14)
    - 1949 (Folder 41: 15)
    - 1950 (Folder 41: 16-18)
    - 1951 (Folder 41: 19)
    - 1952 (Folder 41: 20)
  - Declaration and proclamation, 1944 (Folder 41: 21)
- Yugoslav displaced persons and prisoners of war, 1945-1954 (Box 42-44)
  Material consists of correspondence, including photographs and clippings, reports, lists, and memorandum. Arranged by form
  - Correspondence, 1945-1948
    - 1945 (Folder 42: 1)
    - 1946 (Folder 42: 2-5)
    - 1947 (Folder 42: 6-11)
    - 1948 (Folder 42: 12-14)
  - Reports, lists, and open letter, 1945-1954
    - Logor Mauthauzen, 1945 (Folder 42: 15)
    - List of persons made prisoners in Tyrol, 1945 (Folder 42: 16)
    - Un Rapport sur les Yougoslaves, France, 1945 (Folder 42: 17)
    - Liberated Prisoners of War and Refugees in Italy, 1945-1946 (Folder 42: 18)
    - Logor Eboli, materijalno stanje, 1945-1946 (Folder 42: 19)
    - Logori u americkoj okupacionoj zoni, 1946 (Folder 43: 1)
    - Yugosalv Army (Allied Ex-PWs) in Bavaria, Germany, 1946 (Folder 43: 2)
    - Situation of the Liberated Prisoners of War of the Royal Yugoslav Army in Germany, 1946 (Folder 43: 3)
    - United Friends of Needy and Displaced Persons of Yugoslavia, 1946-1947 (Folder 43: 4)
    - Yugoslav Military Personnel Requesting Asylum in Italy for Political Reasons, 1947-1954 (Folder 43: 5)
    - To President Harry S. Truman from Serbs in Paris, an open letter, 1947 (Folder 43: 6)
    - Ex-Royal Yugoslav Personnel in IRO Camp Pagani, Italy, 1948 (Folder 43: 7)
    - Resettlement Activities in the Markt Pongau Assembly Centre, Austria, 1948-1949 (Folder 43: 8)
    - Yugoslavs Apply for Immigration to the United States, 1949 (Folder 43: 9)
    - Tubercular Patients, Invalids, Old and Disabled Men, Germany, 1950 (Folder 43: 10)
  - Immigration to the Dominican Republic material, 1947-1948
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Folder 43: 11-17)
    - List of applicants, San Domingo, 1947 (Folder 43: 18)
    - Committee for settling Yugoslav displaced persons, 1947 (Folder 43: 19)
  - Displaced Persons Camps (D.P.C.) reports, 1947
    - Trani, Italy
      - Serbs, List No.1 (Folder 43: 20)
      - Slovenians, List No.2 (Folder 43: 21)
      - Croats, List No.3 (Folder 43: 22)
    - Jesi, Italy
      - Serbs, List No.4 (Folder 43: 23)
      - Slovenians, List No.5 (Folder 43: 24)
      - Croats, List No.6 (Folder 43: 25)
    - Ciampino, Italy, Ex-Royal Air Force (R.A.F.) Serbs, List No.7 (Folder 43: 26)
    - List for immigration, List No.8 (Folder 43: 27)
    - Yugoslav, Ex-R.A.F. personnel, List No.9 (Folder 43: 28)
    - Bari, Italy, Serbs, Croats, Slovenians, List No.10 (Folder 44: 1)
    - Outside camps reports, 1947
      - Serbs, List No.11 (Folder 44: 2)
      - Slovenians, List No.12 (Folder 44: 3)
      - Croats, List No.13 (Folder 44: 4)
    - International refugee organizations, 1946-1949
      - Russians (ex-Yugoslav citizens), List, No. 14 (Folder 44: 5)
      - Serbs, List No.15 (Folder 44: 6)
      - Serbs, Croats, Slovenians, 1st additional list, List No.16 (Folder 44: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1949 (Folder 44: 8-10)
    - Reports and memoranda, 1946-1949
      - Question of refugees, United Nations General Assembly, 1946 (Folder 44: 11)
      - Displaced Persons Act of 1948 (Folder 44: 12)
      - Plan for the resettlement of refugee students and professors resolution, 1948 (Folder 44: 13)
      - Iron curtain refugee project draft, 1949 (Folder 44: 14)
    - Refugee Defense Committee, 1946-1947
      - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Folder 44: 15-17)
      - Report, 1947 (Folder 44: 18)
- Subject file, 1935-1963 (Box 44-46)
  Contains correspondence, reports, financial records, clippings and printed matter. Arranged by subject, then form
  - Serbian Orthodox Church, 1937-1963
    - Correspondence, 1937-1955
      - 1937-1947 (Folder 44: 19-25)
      - 1948-1951 (Folder 45: 1-4)
      - 1954-1955 (Folder 45: 5)
    - Serbian Orthodox Diocese in the United States, 1963 (Folder 45: 6)
    - Dra?a Mihailovic capture and trial materials, 1941-1946
      - Correspondence, 1941-1946 (Folder 45: 7-10)
      - Committee for a Fair Trial for Dra?a Mihailovic, Commission of Inquiry, 1945-1946 (Folder 45: 11)
      - Printed matter, 1946
        - American Srbobran (Folder : 12)
        - Clippings (Folder 45: 13-15)
    - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, 1935-1956
      - Correspondence, 1948-1956
      - 1948-1956 (Folder 45: 16-23)
      - National Bank of the Kingdom of Yugoslavia, 1951-1952 (Folder 46: 1-2)
      - Clippings, 1935, 1950 (Folder 46: 3)
- Tatjna Fotic materials, 1940-1968 and undated (Box 46-52)
  Contains correspondence, articles and drafts, lecture materials, lists, notes, and clippings from Foti?'s wife. Arranged by form or subject
  - Correspondence, 1940-1961 and undated
    - General, 1942-1944 (Folder 46: 4-10)
    - A, 1941-1943 (Folder 46: 11)
    - Art galleries, regarding the exhibitions of Yugoslavian artists, 1941-1944 (Folder 46: 12)
    - B, 1941-1944 (Folder 46: 13)
    - Boncesco, Sylvia, 1961 (Folder 46: 14)
    - C, 1943 (Folder 46: 15)
    - Cabric, Ivanka, 1941-1943 (Folder 46: 16)
    - Chamber Music Guild, 1942 (Folder 46: 17)
    - Community War Fund, undated (Folder 46: 18)
    - D, 1941-1943 (Folder 46: 19)
    - Dionisija, episcope, 1941-1943 (Folder 46: 19-20)
    - E, 1943 (Folder 47: 1)
    - F, 1943-1944 (Folder 47: 2)
    - G, 1942-1943 (Folder 47: 3)
    - H, 1941-1942 (Folder 47: 4)
    - Herzog, Jascha, 1942 (Folder 47: 5)
      Includes programs
    - I, 1941 (Folder 47: 6)
    - J, 1934-1944 (Folder 47: 7)
    - K, 1941-1944 (Folder 47: 8-9)
    - King and Queen of Yugoslavia, 1942-1944 (Folder 47: 10)
    - Klubovi, 1941-1942. (Folder 47: 11)
      Includes letters from John P. Vukasinovich
    - Kolo Srpskih sestara, 1940-1943
      - A-K (Folder 47: 12-14)
      - L-W (Folder 47: 15-17)
    - Lisitchitch, Angelia, 1941 (Folder 47: 18)
    - London Red Cross, 1942-1943. (Folder 47: 19)
      Includes report
    - M, 1941-1944 (Folder 47: 20)
    - "Mlade Chetnice," 1942-1944 (Folder 47: 21)
    - Maletic, Rev. Strahinija, 1941 (Folder 47: 22)
    - Melford, Raquel, 1941-1944 (Folder 47: 23)
    - Mrvicin, Darinka, 1941-1943 (Folder 47: 24)
    - N, 1941-1943 (Folder 47: 25)
    - Oklobzijao, Savka, 1941-1942 (Folder 47: 26)
    - P, 1941-1944 (Folder 47: 27)
    - Pavlovitch-Barrili, Milena, 1940-1946. (Folder 47: 28-29)
      Includes exhibit catalogs
    - Strozzi-Engelmann, de, Violetta (Ljubica Oblak), 1942 (Folder 48: 1)
    - Yugoslav Ladies Organization (Jugoslavenska ?ena), 1941-1943 (Folder 48: 2-3)
  - Office files, 1959-1968
    - Correspondence, 1959-1968 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Trips to Europe, correspondence and expenses, 1960-1961 (Folder 48: 5)
    - Appointment calendars, 1960-1962 (Folder 48: 6)
  - Speeches and writings, 1955-1968 and undated
    - "Anthology of Old Spanish," typescript, circa 1960. (Folder 48: 7-8)
    - "Bistrita," typescript and holograph, and notes, undated (Folder 48: 9)
    - "Chanson de Geste in the Light of Recent Investigations of Balkan Epic Poetry," typescript, undated (Folder 48: 10)
    - "Drame et poésie dans le Geste de Guillaume," holograph, undated (Folder 48: 11)
    - "Ericstudien," typescript and notes, undated (Folder 48: 12)
    - "French canelé," typescript and notes, circa 1960 (Folder 48: 13)
    - "Hurezi," typescript and holograph, and notes, undated (Folder 48: 14)
    - "Hans Krings, Die Geschichte des Wortschatzes der Höflichkeit im Französischen," Romanistichse Versuche und Vorarbeiten, Bonn, typescript, 1961 (Folder 48: 15)
    - "Moldovita," holograph and notes, undated (Folder 48: 16)
    - "Personal Infinity," typescript, 1967 (Folder 48: 17)
    - "Romance Prosody," typescript, circa 1955 (Folder 48: 18)
    - Lecture materials, 1955-1968 and undated
      - French, 1964-1968
        - "The Romance of Perceval in Prose," typescript, 1961 (Folder 49: 1)
        - "Santiago," transcript, undated (Folder 49: 2)
        - Old French, undated (Folder 49: 3)
        - French syntax, 1964 (Folder 49: 4)
        - Medieval French Literature, course outline, 1968 (Folder 49: 5)
      - Romanian, 1955-1966
        - "The Semantic Ramifications of Rumanian Popa, a Study in Balkan "Words and Thinks,'" typescript, 1955 (Folder 49: 6)
        - "Problems of Romanian Abstract Terminology,", undated (Folder 49: 7)
        - Romanian paper for Chicago, typescript, undated (Folder 49: 8)
        - Romanian phonetics, undated (Folder 49: 9)
        - Romanian bibliography, circa 1966 (Folder 49: 10)
    - Notes, typescript and holograph, undated (Folder 49: 11-14)
    - Notebooks, undated (Folder 49: 15)
    - Notes on index cards, undated (Folder 49: 16)
    - Notes on index cards, undated (contd.) (Folder 50: 1)
  - Career file, 1959-1968
    - Catholic University of America, 1966-1968
      - Manual on information for the faculty, 1966 (Folder 50: 2)
      - Manual of procedure in appointments and promotions, 1967 (Folder 50: 3)
      - College reports, circa 1968 (Folder 50: 4)
    - Appointments as an examiner and Chairman for the final oral examinations for the degree, 1968 (Folder 50: 5)
    - Modern Language Association, annual meeting reports and correspondence, 1964, 1967 (Folder 50: 6-7)
    - Conference programs, 1964, 1967, 1968 (Folder 50: 8)
    - Comparative Romance Linguistics newsletters, 1964, 1967 (Folder 50: 9)
    - "Approaches to the Reduction of Ambiguity in Machine Translation," by L. E. Dostert, Journal of the Society of Motion Picture and Television Engineers, April 1959 (Folder 50: 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1968. (Folder 50: 11-12)
    Includes street map, clippings, leaflet, comments, and Cardinal Investment Club reports and correspondence
  - Photographs depicting painting, buildings, car, aircrafts, and streets scenes, 1955 and undated (Folder 50: 13)
  - United Yugoslav Relief Fund Knitting project, 1941-1946
    - Correspondence, 1941-1946
      - General, 1941-1946 (Folder 51: 1-4)
      - Knitting project follow up letters, 1941-1943 (Folder 51: 5)
      - Letters of appeal for Yugoslav women to join the knitting project, 1941-1942 (Folder 51: 6)
      - American Red Cross, 1941-1944 (Folder 51: 7)
    - Reports, 1941-1944
      - Knitting project report, draft, 1942 (Folder 51: 8-9)
      - Prisoners of war parcel description, 1941-1943 (Folder 51: 10-11)
      - Vunena odeca za Jugoslvenske zarobljenike, 1942 (Folder 51: 12)
      - "Poruka Amerike Jugoslaviji," Poslanstvo Kraljevine Jugoslavije, obave?tenje ?tampi, 1942 (Folder 51: 13)
      - Akcija za izradu vunene odece za Jugoslavenske zarobljenike, 1943 (Folder 51: 14)
      - "The Treasurer," special report, 1943 (Folder 51: 15)
      - Diplomas for knitting, 1943-1944 (Folder 51: 16)
      - Diplomas sent list, 1944 (Folder 51: 17)
      - Diploma acceptance letters, 1943-1944 (Folder 51: 18-19)
    - Printed matter, 1941-1943
      - Clippings, 1941 (Folder 51: 20-21)
      - The United Yugoslav Relief Fund leaflet, 1943 (Folder 52: 1)
  - American Friends of Yugoslavia correspondence, 1941-1944
    - General, 1941 (Folder 52: 2)
    - Washington Committee, 1941-1944. (Folder 52: 3-7)
      Includes three stamps issued by Greek government for the Greek War Relief Fund
    - Ilija Belo?evic, Nürnberg, Germany, package wrapping paper, undated (Folder 52: 8)
- Printed matter, 1934-1968 (Box 52-60)
  Includes daily newspapers, serial issues, bulletins, articles, news reports and press releases, clippings and photographs. Arranged by form
  - Daily newspapers, bulletins, and articles, 1934-1968
    - Amerikanski Srbobran, 1936-1959 (Folder 52: 9-19)
    - Ameri?ka Domovina, 1948 (Folder 52: 20)
    - Avala, Balkan news service, no.74, 1949 (Folder 52: 21)
    - B.I.S., Bilten Informativne Slu?be, 1950 (Folder 53: 1)
    - Borba, Mar-50 (Folder 53: 2)
    - "British Speeches of the Day," British Information Service, Mar-44 (Folder 53: 3)
    - "The Case of Archbishop Stepinac," Embassy of the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, Washington D.C., 1947 (Folder 53: 4)
    - The Case of General Mihailovich (Mihailovic) by John Plamenatz, London, 1944 (Folder 53: 5)
    - Congressional Record extracts, February-March 1945 (Folder 53: 6)
    - Congressional Record, December 1950 (Folder 53: 7-10)
    - "Considérations sur la situation actuelle de la Yougoslavie et la politique suivie vis-ï¿½-vis d'elle," typescript, by M. J. ?ujovic, 1949 (Folder 53: 11)
    - Ce?alj, November 1943 (Folder 53: 12)
    - "The Declaration of Liberation," National Committee for a Free Europe, 1951 (Folder 53: 13)
    - "The Defenders of the Constitution and Their Administration (1838-1858)," by Slobodan Yovanovich (Jovanovic), typescript, undated (Folder 53: 14)
    - Demokracija, May 1959 (Folder 53: 15)
    - The Department of State Bulletin, Vol. XVI, No.416, June 1947 and Vol. XVII, No. 440A (Folder 53: 16)
    - "Le Désastre de la Yougoslavie et le Général Douchan Simovitch" (Du?an Simovic) by D. Radonitch, typescript, 1942 (Folder 53: 17)
    - Dinarski Glasnik, May 1949 (Folder 53: 18)
    - Dokumente zum Konflikt mit Jugoslavwien und Griechenland, Berlin, 1941 (Folder 53: 19)
    - U Domovini, January 1948 (Folder 53: 20)
    - Dragi?a Vasic, by Mladen Vasic, Srpski Narodni Savez, 1948 (Folder 53: 21)
    - "Edward R. Murrow with the News C.B.S. Radio Network," transcript, 1956 (Folder 53: 22)
    - The Evening Star, June 1944 (Folder 53: 23)
    - "The Foreign and Domestic Policies of Yugoslavia," press conference with J. Tito, The Yugoslav Information Centre, transcript, 1952 (Folder 53: 24)
    - "Forced Labour in Albania," by Kemal Vokopola, reprint, circa 1955 (Folder 54: 1)
    - "Forced Labour in Czechoslovakia," by Jaroslav Jira, reprint, circa 1955 (Folder 54: 2)
    - "Forced Labour in Hungary," by Alexander Bedo, George Torzsay-Biber, and Leslie LeNard, reprint, circa 1955 (Folder 54: 3)
    - "Forced Labour in Poland as of January 7, 1955," by Stefan Rosada and Gwozdz, reprint (Folder 54: 4)
    - "Forced Labour in Rumania," reprint, circa 1955 (Folder 54: 5)
    - Glas Kanadskih Srba, May 1959 (Folder 54: 6)
    - Glas Izbegle Jugoslavije, October and December 1947 (Folder 54: 7)
    - Glas Ravne Gore, June 1949, March 1950 (Folder 54: 8)
    - Glas Srba, June 1947, January 1949 (Folder 54: 9)
    - Hermes, March, 1949 (Folder 54: 10)
    - Hrvatski Glas, March 1948 (Folder 54: 11)
    - Hrvatski List and Danica Hrvatska, November 1941 (Folder 54: 12)
    - Information Bulletin, February 1945 (Folder 54: 13)
    - Inside of Yugoslavia, by Louis Adamic, Acron Press, 1942 (Folder 54: 14)
    - Intermarium ou Le Moyen-Orient Europï¿½en, No.5/6, 1947 (Folder 54: 15)
    - The Intermarium Bulletin, No. 6, 1947 (Folder 54: 16)
    - Iskra, April 1954, May 1959 (Folder 54: 17)
    - Jugoslovenska Otad?bina, January 1946 (Folder 54: 18)
    - Kanadski Srbobran, May-June 1959 (Folder 54: 19)
    - The League of Nations, Fifteenth ordinary session of the assembly, delegation and members of delegation list, Geneva, 1934 (Folder 54: 20)
    - "Macedonian Violence," by Sta?a Karkov, typescript, 1949 (Folder 54: 21)
      Includes Fotic's correspondence
    - Memorandum of the General Assembly of the United Nations, Washington D.C., 1950 (Folder 54: 22)
    - Memorandum to the President of the United States, Washington, 1945 (Folder 54: 23)
    - "Moj ?ivot," by Petra II, King of Royal Yugoslavia, typescript, 1952 (Folder 54: 24)
    - La Nation Roumaine, July 1950 (Folder 54: 25)
    - "National Problems and Patisan Yugslavia," by Dinko Toma?ic, Journal of Central European Affairs reprint, Vol. 6, No. 2, 1946 (Folder 54: 26)
    - "My Native Land," by Louis Adamic, Sunday Star, 1943 (Folder 54: 27)
    - Na?a Rec, May and July 1948, October and May 1949, January 1954 (Folder 54: 28)
    - The New Palestine, December 1942 (Folder 54: 29)
    - Neuw Volks-Zeitung, May 1941 (Folder 54: 30)
    - The New Leader, May-June, and August 1946, September 1951 (Folder 54: 31)
    - New York Times, March 1941, January and September 1947 (Folder 55: 1-2)
    - "New Yugoslavia," Yugoslav Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1946 (Folder 55: 3)
    - The Nineteenth Century and After, January 1944 (Folder 55: 4)
    - Otad?bina, Godina II, 1946, Godina IV, 1948 (Folder 55: 5-6)
    - Oslobodenje, November, 1948, February 1949 (Folder 55: 7)
    - O?i?ani Je?, January 1941 (Folder 55: 8)
    - Poems by Milan Dedinac, transcript, undated (Folder 55: 9)
    - PM Daily, July 1946 (Folder 55: 10)
    - Pod Maslinama, No.2, 1947 (Folder 55: 11)
    - Politika, 1946-1954
    - May and July, 1946 (Folder 55: 12-13)
    - January, April, December, 1947 (Folder 55: 14-18)
    - January-February, 1948 (Folder 55: 19)
    - January, 1954 (Folder 56: 1)
    - Poruka, 1950 (Folder 56: 2)
    - "Pourquoi ai-je choisi juste ce moment pour quitter mon pays?", undated (Folder 56: 3)
    - Predstavka Srpskog Narodnog Saveta povodom izbora u Jugoslaviji, open letter, circa 1945 (Folder 56: 4)
    - Pregled, No.6-7, 1948, No. 4, 1951 (Folder 56: 5-6)
    - "The President of the General Assembly of the United Nations," International Pleasant Union, 1945 (Folder 56: 7)
    - Prevent World War II, No.38, 1951 (Folder 56: 8)
    - "The Prime Minister Review," The Times, May 1944 (Folder 56: 9)
    - "Rapport no. 6, sur l'activité en faveur des ex-prisonniers de guerre et autres Yougoslaves, réfugiés et DP," United Nation Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1946-1947 (Folder 56: 10)
    - Ravna Gora, No.8, No.9, 1945, No.10, No.11, 1946 (Folder 56: 11)
    - Ravnogorac, October and December 1947 (Folder 56: 12)
    - "The Re-Creation of Yugoslavia," The United Committee of South-Slavic Americans, 1944 (Folder 56: 13)
    - Report of Commission of Inquiry, Committee for a Fair Trial for Dra?a Mihailovic, May 1946 (Folder 56: 14)
    - Resolution and Reports from September 1954 to January 1955, Assembly of Captive European Nations (Folder 56: 15-18)
    - Rodoljub, December 1945 (Folder 56: 19)
    - "Statistika spljne trgovine Kraljevine Jugoslvije za 1935 godinu," Dr?avna ?tamparija, Belgrade,Serbia, 1936 (Folder 56: 20)
    - Saturday Review of Literature, November 1948 (Folder 57: 1)
    - Seljacka Jugoslavija, May-June, 1947 (Folder 57: 2)
    - "Serbian Report on Yugoslavia," National Committee for a Free Europe, 1952 (Folder 57: 3)
    - Sindikalist, October 1950 (Folder 57: 4)
    - Sloboda, May-June 1959 (Folder 57: 5)
    - Slobodna Rec, May 1940, October 1942 (Folder 57: 6)
    - Sloga, April 1947 (Folder 57: 7)
    - Slovenska Dr?ava, 1950 (Folder 57: 8)
    - Srpska Borba, May and February 1950, May-June 1959 (Folder 57: 9-11)
    - Srpski Glas, No.4, No. 5, 1948 (Folder 57: 12)
    - Srpske Novine, No.2, 1946, No.9-10, 15-16, 1947 (Folder 57: 13-14)
    - The Sunday Star, January 1947 (Folder 57: 15)
    - Telegraphic Agency New Yugoslavia, Information Bulletin, No. 2, No. 6 (Folder 57: 16)
    - Time, January 1943 (Folder 57: 17)
    - The Times, March 1946 (Folder 57: 18)
    - "Tito visit Marks another Victory for Communism," by Edgar Ansel Mowrer, General Features Cooperation, reprint, 1946 (Folder 57: 19)
    - "Tragedija Blakanskog Orla," Beogradski process, 1946 (Folder 57: 20)
    - Trade Union Conference in London, Eight World Congress of Comintern, 1945 (Folder 57: 21)
    - Trends and Tides, January-February 1946, July-September 1947 (Folder 57: 22)
    - "True Conditions in Yugoslavia," by Louis, undated (Folder 57: 23)
    - Vers L'Union, Paris, 1947 (Folder 57: 24)
    - Vjesnik, February-March, 1950 (Folder 57: 25)
    - La Voz Libre de Yugoslavia, 1945 (Folder 57: 26)
    - The Washington Post, July 1944, October 1954 (Folder 57: 27-28)
    - The Weekly Review, October and December 1943 (Folder 58: 1)
    - Yugoslavia, October 1942, November 1943 (Folder 58: 2)